[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 25]
Disrespect the fire moth,
and calamity shall descend from the heavens.
These words
likely contain a hidden threat as well.
If we insist on continuing the investigation
and preventing them from causing trouble,
you and your loved ones
may face unexpected disasters.
How could you say this to Madam?
Are you deliberately
trying to make her worry?
With her intelligence,
it would be only a matter of time before she figured it out.
-I…
-I just gave her
an early reminder.
♫I hope you also look up and see the radiant stars and moon♫
♫No matter how vast the world is, I'll wait for your appearance♫
♫A quick glance at each other♫
♫Has warmed the winter in memories♫
♫Don't mind the destined solitude, and shine brightly♫
♫I'll wait until the years blossom like flowers♫
♫The ice and snow slowly melted♫
♫I heard those tender words♫
♫He told her, "I love you"♫
What's wrong?
♫What I saw in my dreams♫
Have you seen a doctor?
♫Is not a flashy illusion♫
♫I don't fear the challenges ahead, riding a white horse to chase after time♫
I'm fine.
Thank you for your concern.
♫Let's go together♫
Don't push yourself.
I'll be worried.
♫Love is pure and flawless, indifferent to the changes of the world♫
♫Let's experience it together♫
You mustn't fall ill.
Otherwise,
who else will make medicinal dishes for me?
Shen Du,
I really don't have the energy
to bicker with you today.
Alright.
I misspoke earlier.
What's wrong with you?
Shen Du,
I enjoy investigating cases.
I can lose myself in the pursuit of the truth.
But I don't want to drag my family into it.
The Fire Moth Sect
sent me a message with the words on the corpse.
They've planned everything from the start
and are deliberately putting on a show for us.
They're demonstrating their power.
This is a warning.
You are afraid that continuing the investigation
will implicate your family.
Back in Xiang'an,
if we hadn't arrived in time,
Sister Caiwei and the others
would have already lost their lives.
If...
If, while I'm in Yingzhou,
they really
go after my family,
what should I do?
I'll be far away from them.
How can I ensure their safety?
I thought about it for four hours,
but I just couldn't come up with a solution.
If you're willing,
I can send a carriage to take you back to Xiang'an.
As for the matters in Yingzhou,
you don't need to worry about them.
And what about you?
What are you going to do?
Me?
Honey, do you want me
to personally escort you back
to your maiden home?
We can't go back.
You are the Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau,
and I am the Secretary of the Ministry of Justice.
We are here
on a mission.
I knew
you would never leave.
A brief emotional moment
wouldn't shake your passion for solving cases.
Don't act like
you know me so well.
You've come to your senses?
This is the Yan Xing I know—
sharp-tongued and unsparing.
And of course,
fearless in the face of authority,
with a stubborn determination to charge into danger.
I...
I know you're worried about
your family's safety.
I, Shen Du, give you my word:
what you fear
will never happen.
Before coming Gannan Area,
I made preparations.
As things stand now,
everything is under control.
Do you remember
that letter from Xiang'an?
An urgent letter from Xiang'an?
Who sent it?
Madam Xu.
Of course I remember.
Every year during the Clothing Bestowal Festival,
the Grand Empress Dowager
would go to
Mount Li Hot Springs Villa for recuperation.
She would also reward some ministers' families,
allowing them to travel and rest with her.
The letter from Madam Xu informed me
that she has already arranged for the Yan family
to be included in the entourage list.
Within Her Majesty's
line of sight,
I believe no sect
would dare to make any reckless moves.
Well played, Shen Du.
But come to think of it,
there is indeed something that,
while not very important,
is still
related to you.
What is it?
About that headless corpse case,
Ji Dafu, the suspect's brother-in-law,
is here.
This Ji Dafu
has a rather unique identity,
as both the victim and the suspect
are his wife's biological brothers.
Please, I beg you,
give me a way out, alright?
[Ji Dafu]
When will the case
of my brother-in-law be concluded?
If the head can't be found,
I'll accept it.
Can we at least
let the body be buried soon?
Ji Dafu,
calm down.
This case is still under investigation.
Governor Mo,
you're looking for me?
I heard you have some new suggestions
about the case.
There are some unusual aspects in this case
which I'm still investigating.
My suggestion is
to combine this case with the bride case
for a joint investigation.
If we combine the cases,
the investigation
will be further delayed.
I'm afraid...
Mr. Pan,
what do you mean?
I think your title as the top detective
is undeserved.
You even set a rule
of never meeting with your clients face-to-face.
I think you're just afraid
of failing
and losing face.
Today,
in front of Lord Mo,
give me a straightforward answer.
Within five days, will you solve the case
and catch the murderer?
If not,
refund my money,
so I can find someone more capable.
If I can't solve the case,
I will refund the money.
But I've almost
figured out who the murderer is.
Who is the murderer?
The murderer is...
a Half-faced Ghost.
The ghost theory
your friend used
to avoid refunding the money
really worked.
After hearing it, Ji Dafu
was stunned and then left.
But Governor Mo
wasn't so easy to fool.
Mr. Pan,
I have already reported the bride case to the Ministry of Justice
for case closure.
Governor Mo,
I provided a new testimony.
I've seen it.
Then why are you closing this case so hastily?
Xu Jize now has a new testimony.
He may be given a lighter sentence.
The eyeless corpse case is clearly a case within a case
and is closely connected to the headless corpse case.
Mr. Pan,
this is not Xiang'an!
This is not Xiang'an.
This is Yingzhou,
which was once mired in decades of military conflict.
The situation in Yingzhou is unstable.
Although our country has set a governor here,
Xichen is still eyeing it with great caution.
Historically,
it has been occupied by Xichen multiple times.
To quell the chaos in the Western Region
and prevent another war,
the crucial thing is to unite the people.
But do you know what we rely on
to unite them?
I'd like to hear it.
What we rely on
is long-term stability,
strict laws to eliminate crime,
solving every case,
and capturing every thief.
We need to make the people believe
that as long as the officials of Cang State
are in charge,
Yingzhou
will always be a city
where the citizens can live in peace.
So,
in times of chaos, heavy punishment is necessary.
Xu Jize's head
is destined to hang on the city gate,
becoming the head
that strikes fear in people's hearts, right?
Er Laipi is extremely vicious,
and his crimes are beyond redemption.
There's no need for further investigation.
Xu Jize,
who raped a married woman,
deserves an even harsher punishment.
Violating the laws of the frontier
is a capital offense.
However, I can promise you
that he will die peacefully,
without becoming
the head hanging on the city gate.
You told me all this
in such detail
not just to tell me
how embarrassed Pan Chi was today, right?
You want to tell me
that I should understand Governor Mo's
intervention in the case
and his urgency in reaching a quick conclusion.
His position means
he cannot, like us,
focus solely on pursuing the truth of the case.
You're reminding me
to pay more attention to
Governor Mo's situation
and not to doubt
that he has a heart for the people.
I want to tell you
that people are complex,
and we shouldn't jump to conclusions so quickly.
Shen Du.
Shen Du?
How much do you
trust Mo Qianzhi?
He used to be the person I trusted the most.
And now?
Now...
he is the person I most want to trust.
To uncover the truth,
one must inevitably go through the process
you're going through now.
No matter how small the detail
or how close the person,
first, don't be afraid to doubt;
you must have the courage to verify them.
Trust
can also be
a force in investigation.
The Fire Moth Sect has deep roots in Yingzhou.
Shen has a close relationship with Mo.
[Jiang's Mansion]
-Go.
-Please take another look.
Go!
-Go!
Stop talking.
-Take another look!
Leave now!
[Jiang's Mansion]
Sir.
Please bring me another pot of wine.
Certainly.
Yan Xing?
Why are you here?
Take a look.
Sir, take a look.
[Grain]
Take a look.
These are all new styles.
Lady Xing,
what are you doing here?
I...
came to walk my pigeon.
Walk your pigeon?
Sixth Lady,
do you know
that the specialty of this restaurant
is roasted pigeon?
But speaking of which,
isn't it a bit cruel
to do this
to the pigeon?
Making it watch with its own eyes
that it'll inevitably face death.
A toast
to this poor pigeon.
You're not here drowning your sorrows
in alcohol
because Ji Dafu said you were incompetent
this afternoon, are you?
Indeed, good news doesn't travel far,
but bad news spreads quickly.
Ji Dafu is nothing
in my eyes.
His words
are not worth me taking to heart.
So, is this because of
the case closing?
I heard that about the bride case,
you got new testimonies.
Did you find anything?
Found anything?
No, nothing.
They're just some useless testimonies.
However,
to gather the evidence,
I went to the prison to visit Xu Jize.
After questioning him,
when I was about to leave,
he suddenly said to me—
Mr. Pan.
You're also
a scholar with a humble background, right?
With your courage and eloquence,
why aren't you an official in the Ministry of Justice,
but rather some kind of
folk detective?
Let me make a bold guess.
You and I are the same kind of people,
burdened by our humble origins.
[Huang's Mansion]
Please don't close the door.
My poetry has already been
submitted to your office for more than a month.
Has Senior Minister Huang reviewed it yet?
What a stubborn stray dog.
With his pathetic appearance,
he actually expects our master to recommend him.
[Huang's Mansion]
Our paths are different.
No matter how much resentment I have,
I would never
vent my frustration on the weak.
The weak?
No.
I never bully the weak.
I only bully
the noble families
who have been suppressing and humiliating
the humble families!
They are born into positions of power,
treating us from humble backgrounds
as their servants.
I did defile one of their brides.
I just wanted them to taste
the flavor of humiliation.
The taste that we,
the scholars from humble backgrounds,
have been bitterly swallowing every day for a hundred years.
Now that things have come to this point,
you still don't think you were wrong?
I do.
Yes. In the case of Lady Du,
I made the mistake of not investigating thoroughly.
By "not investigating thoroughly,"
you mean that at the beginning of the case,
you realized that the Li family
couldn't be considered a gentry family, right?
As expected of the top detective.
After Lady Du was taken away,
Er Laipi said
that the Li family was a wealthy household.
Originally, it was Li Hongfa
who started with a small business and made a fortune.
But he was determined
to have his son enter officialdom.
Just because
merchants are the lowest class in society,
Li Zimo was like me.
Later, Li Hongfa spent a lot of money
to whitewash himself
with a fake identity as a descendant of a gentry family.
Then Li Zimo
was able to take the exam.
So, in the end, you decided
to stop committing the crime
and started arguing with Er Laipi.
Yes.
We had a fierce argument.
Later, we realized
we were being followed, so we stopped arguing.
But from the beginning,
I always wanted
to send Lady Du back.
Who knew we'd stumble upon a murder case?
I really didn't kill Er Laipi.
And I
sent Du Xiaowan back almost unscathed.
I'll report
what you said today truthfully
for sentencing.
According to the law,
you might get a lighter sentence.
But in my heart,
you are nothing but
an absolute coward.
The brave
get angry at the stronger,
while the cowardly
get angry at the weaker.
You didn't dare to confront the powerful forces
that had been oppressing you.
Instead, you turn your attention
to defenseless women.
That wasn't revenge.
You're just a coward
who only bullies kind people.
The sentencing
is already over.
I'm certain to die.
You just came to Yingzhou
and don't know much about Governor Mo.
From the day I got here,
I never expected to leave alive.
You're right.
I brought this upon myself.
I dug my own grave.
No.
I shouldn't have been born into this world.
In the next life,
I would rather be
an illiterate peasant
than a scholar
who only understands things
roughly.
Stop drinking.
Sir,
don't serve him any more alcohol.
Bring him a bowl of lamb noodle soup.
Alright, sure thing.
Here you go.
The lamb from Gannan Area
is famously delicious.
Trust me,
rather than drowning your sorrows in alcohol,
it's better to soothe them with a bowl of soup noodles.
Give it a try.
How is it?
The taste is indeed quite good.
See? I didn't lie to you, didn't I?
Laughing heartily to the sky,
I stride across the divine land.
Though the noble deem themselves precious,
I see them as mere dust.
Though the humble consider themselves lowly,
who's to say they're not worth a thousand gold?
I shake my robes and gaze upon the mountains,
washing my feet in the long river.
Sixth Lady,
why did you suddenly recite this?
I just feel that
this manifesto is bold and grand.
With just a few words, it exposes the fact
that scholars from humble backgrounds are being oppressed.
It's so invigorating.
Once this poem was made,
it spread across the teahouses and taverns of the Imperial City.
During those days,
the sons of noble families in Xiang'an City
didn't even dare to be too ostentatious
when dining out,
afraid of provoking the simmering public resentment.
With all this buildup,
you're surely not just
trying to flatter my literary talent, right?
Of course, it's not just that.
There's one more thing I want to praise you for.
I admire your courage.
As long as one retains the courage
to challenge decayed authority,
sometimes just a single word
or poem
can carry great power.
I know that
the current situation of the humble families in Cang State
is disappointing you.
But as long as each
and every one of us doesn't give up,
I believe there will come a day
when the clouds part and the sun shines
on the scholars
from humble backgrounds.
I don't know
if it's because this bowl of noodles is so delicious
or your words
have had an inspiring effect,
but I now feel refreshed
and could investigate 10 more cases.
No, no, no.
There can't be any more cases
in Gannan Area.
You're already
so busy with investigations
that you have no time to rest.
If more cases come up,
you really won't be able to keep up.
There's something
I still want to tell you.
If you're being abused,
you don't have to endure it.
Who says that
the White Ghost's mansion
is a place you can enter but can't leave?
In my opinion,
Shen Du is just a paper tiger.
Just say the word,
and I, Pan Chi,
will risk any danger
to help you out of this misery.
You... you must have misunderstood something.
No one is abusing me.
No one is abusing you?
Then how did you get that wound
on your forehead?
Every time I see you,
there are always wounds on you.
Could it be that you didn't get them at home?
It's true that I got them at home.
How should I explain this to you?
Anyway,
Shen Du really isn't mistreating me.
Although my marrying into the Shen family as a replacement bride
was a bit absurd
and not what he wanted,
overall,
Shen Du has been a decent husband.
He takes good care
of me and my family.
Besides,
I will eventually leave him.
Both Shen Du
and I
are well aware
that this day will come soon.
Why?
Because there has always been
someone else in his heart.
And that person is not me.
This position
was never meant for me.
Madam,
considering how busy you've been with work lately,
Governor Mo has kindly arranged for you
to visit the most famous hot springs in Yingzhou,
Yixi Pond, to relax and bathe.
Young lady,
our Yixi Pond
is no worse than the royal family's Mount Li Hot Springs.
It's fed by thousand-year-old spring water
from Xiling Mountain
and enhanced by natural geothermal heat,
with dozens of different herbs
in the pond.
For men, it strengthens the kidneys and replenishes Yang energy;
for women, it enhances beauty and nourishes the skin.
Its effectiveness is widely acclaimed.
Within a hundred miles of Gannan Area,
all couples hoping for children
specifically come to bathe
in this pond.
Thank you for the explanation.
You've worked hard guiding me.
You may take a break now.
Oh no, I can't.
I haven't served you
in putting on your silk robe yet.
Who's there?
It's me.
Why are you here?
Naturally...
I'm here to take a bath.
This is the women's bath.
You should go to another pond.
Yixi Pond only has one pond.
There's no separation for men and women.
Besides, the Yingzhou government arranged
for us to bathe together as a married couple.
If we bathe separately,
won't it be too strange?
What would the people outside think?
The people outside?
There are a few housemaids and servants
watching.
Even if it's just for show,
I should bathe with you.
I'm getting in now.
Wait, wait!
Don't get in yet.
Turn your back
and close your eyes.
Are you too shy
to bathe with me?
I'm not!
I'm just afraid you'll be awkward
and make me feel embarrassed.
Okay, you can open your eyes now.
Get in now.
I can't see anything now.
Where should I get in from?
Oh no.
His eyesight is poor.
I should've left a light on for him
and waited until he came down before blowing it out.
Wait there.
I'll help you.
You said someone
has always been in my heart.
Who is that person?
Mo Xiuxiu?
No.
That would expose the fact
that I overheard him talking to Mo Qianzhi.
Shen Du,
why did you eavesdrop on me?
Couldn't you just
ask me frankly?
If I ask now,
will you dare to answer?
Of course, I will.
I have always heard that
you have a reputation for not being fond of women.
I completely agree with that.
In Shen's Mansion,
there are no concubines,
and even female servants are rare.
Moreover,
you've shown dislike towards me many times.
Doesn't this say enough?
I stay away from women
because there's already
a girl I like.
So I misunderstood you.
I met her
when we were kids.
I still keep her
woven pig figurine.
Because of her,
I managed to survive in
the Prisoner's Center.
Yes.
Thanks to Mo Xiuxiu's brother pleading for him,
he was spared the death penalty
and sent to the Prisoner's Center.
Every night,
she sneaked into the back garden
and brought me comfort and food.
In those days of endless darkness,
she was the light
I desperately longed for each night.
I didn't even know
her name
or see her face clearly.
The only gift I gave her
was a copper whistle.
This whistle was given to me by my father.
I remember she told me
that one day,
she would take me out aboveboard.
One day,
I will clear the Shen family's name
and get you out of here aboveboard.
For many years after that,
I never saw her again.
She seemed to have vanished without a trace.
Until one day,
as if by fate,
she became my wife.
♫The night is still young, and the moonlight reflects on the west window♫
But ironically,
♫There are stars in your eyes♫
at that time,
♫When I touch you♫
I didn't even know
she was the girl from my memories.
♫My heart is like a flickering candlelight, shaking and swaying♫
♫The more I care, the deeper I hide♫
Later, I found out.
I hope it was not too late.
♫Leaves turn yellow and fall, and my thoughts run in thousands of lines♫
♫Time is like a poem, romantic and sorrowful♫
I want to tell her
♫Two hearts♫
that in my heart,
♫Collide between dawn and dusk♫
from the beginning,
♫The embrace came as a surprise♫
it has always been her.
♫Every memory, I hold it dear♫
♫From desolation, it has become a poem♫
♫Looking back♫
♫We passed through the misty rain and waited for the sunny day♫
♫Love ripples in each other's eyes♫
♫You have long melted the frost in my heart♫
♫So many words to say, but the paper isn't long enough♫
♫Every day♫
♫We test and probe each other♫
♫And before we knew it, we reached forever♫
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
♫I want to keep you by my side♫
♫Through the obstacle of wind and rain♫
♫I want to be your moonlight♫
♫Accompany you until every dawn♫
♫How I wish♫
♫I could just forget the passage of time like this♫
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
♫May we never forget each other♫
♫There will always be a place for us to meet♫
♫I want to be with you forever♫
♫When our black hair turns grey♫
♫In this life♫
♫I'll only cherish you in my heart♫
-I...
-You...
-I…
You go first.
How did you know
that woven pig was made by me?
Is this
what you've been hesitating
to ask all along?
I knew from the very beginning
that it wasn't made by Xiuxiu.
You're amazing.
I also want to make one
as a birthday gift for Brother Du.
But no matter how I try,
it always turns out ugly.
Can you...
swap with me?
Sure, you can have it.
Thank you.
You're so nice.
[Shen's Mansion]
On my birthday,
I received the little pig.
I originally wanted to find a reason
to thank you.
But then I learned that you had been taken away by your family.
At the time, I was so absorbed
in the happiness of knowing that my father
hadn't abandoned me.
He was late because of official business,
and I didn't notice anything else.
I never expected
that you would still keep the woven pig.
Later,
the Shen family was confiscated.
This woven pig
became one of the few things
that could be kept.
So, I've kept it ever since.
It reminds me
of the good times when my father
taught me how to weave.
It was only recently that I learned
that this Sixth Lady is Sixth Lady Yan.
The Prisoner's Center...
You always said you would come to take me out.
Why didn't you come later?
Because
I always crawled in through the dog hole
in the back garden.
Later, they discovered
this loophole
and blocked it up.
After that,
you didn't need me to take you out anymore.
Thank you.
You came to take me home anyway.